♪～
～♪
And then you take this
and give it a good tug.
（リーン）そしたらね
ここを こうキュキュッと…
A good tug.
（フシ）キュキュッと
Hey, Fushi-san...
ねえ フシさん 来月ね
I'm having my sixteenth
birthday party next month.
私の16歳の
誕生日パーティーがあるの
Would you and Gugu like to come?
グーグーと一緒に
いらっしゃらない？
Sure. I'll let Gugu know.
うん グーグーに言っとく
I'm so happy.
わあ よかった
Fushi has not transformed once
in the past four years.
（観察者）フシは この４年間
一度も変身をしなかった
Since he never regenerated
by changing forms,
変身による形状の再現を
行わないことによって
his body aged in accordance
with the time that had passed.
彼の肉体は正しく時間を刻み
相応に成長した
There were two reasons
he never changed forms.
姿を変えなかった理由は
２つあった
First is that he was fortunate enough to
never encounter his archenemy, the Nokkers.
１つは
幸いにも 敵であるノッカーが
襲来しなかったためである
The second is that Fushi
himself had chosen so.
２つ目はフシ自身が
そうしようと決めたからである
It seems he wanted to experience life
変身しないグーグーたちと
同じように⸺
the same way Gugu and the others
do: without transforming.
過ごしてみたかったようだ
To that end, he also never created anything.
それゆえ 物を作り出すことも
しなかった
If you ask me,
私に言わせれば
life as a human being is a repetition of
mundane days, lacking in stimulation.
人間の生活とは
刺激の少ない日々の連続である
Naturally, there's also little to gain.
当然 獲得したものも少ない
For example, a stone crayfish.
たとえば石ザリガニ
A thread shrimp.
イトエビ
A wet cloth and bucket.
ぬれた布と桶(おけ)
Meer the dog.
犬のミール
A pot.
鍋
A stone weight.
重りの石
Pottery shards.
陶器の破片
A nasty potato.
えぐいイモ
And a sewing needle.
そして裁縫針
Did you poke yourself?
（フシ）うっ
（リーン）刺したの？
Oh, no! I'll ask the old man
for some disinfectant.
大変！　おじいさんに
消毒液をもらってくるわ
I'm fine.
大丈夫
これくらい 全然 へいき
It's not a big deal.
Are you sure?
え… そう？
So... what were we talking about again?
それで… 何の話してたんだっけ？
What does Gugu like?
グーグーの好きなものは何かって
Oh, Gugu likes crayfish.
（フシ）ああ グーグーは
ザリガニが好きだよ
Crayfish?
ザリガニ？
All right.
分かった パーティーの日に
用意しておくわ
I'll cook some on the day of the party.
Oh, I know! If I make him a shirt,
do you think he'll wear it?
そうだ 上の服を作ったら
着てくれるかしら？
I've never seen him wearing a shirt.
着てるとこ見たことない
I wonder if there's anything he'd
want that I could make him.
（リーン）
うーん… 私が作れるもので
何か欲しいものって あるのかな？
He was saying he wanted a rag for his feet.
足拭き用の ぞうきんが
欲しいって言ってたよ
A rag...
ぞうきん… なんかヤダわ
I'd rather not.
Why not?
なんで？
I'm sure he'd appreciate
anything you give him.
リーンに もらったものなら
何でも喜ぶと思うけど
ん～ ホントに？
Are you sure?
Gift From the Past
You know...
（リーン）私ね…
I have to get married when I'm sixteen.
16になったら
結婚しなきゃいけないの
To the person my parents chose for me.
親が決めた相手と…
Do you know what "getting married" is?
分かる 結婚？
ううん
Getting married means I have
to become like my mom.
結婚するって 私が
私のママみたいになるってことよ
I get together with some person I don't love
and give birth to some snotty brat.
愛してない人と一緒になって
生意気な子供を産むの
And you don't want that?
イヤなの？
Of course not.
当たり前よ
I've never even really seen his face.
だって 相手は
顔も見たことないような人なのよ
Does he wear a mask? Like Gugu?
仮面かぶってるの？
グーグーみたいに？
That's not what I mean.
そうゆう意味じゃなくて…
First of all, I'm not marrying
someone I don't like.
まずね 好きな人との
結婚じゃなきゃ ありえない！
So I'm thinking of introducing my boyfriend
to Mom and Dad at the birthday party.
だから私 誕生日パーティーで
私の恋人を
パパとママに紹介しようと思うの
Which means, before that...
Before that, I need to get a boyfriend.
だから それまでに…
それまでに恋人を作らなきゃなの！
Which means I need to become
close with someone I like.
そのためには好きな人と
いい感じになって…
Become... close...
いい感じに…
I have to make it work.
がんばらなきゃ…
This... is kind of like how it feels
when Gugu's talking to you.
この感じ… グーグーが
リーンと話すときに似てる
Is this thing you're feeling
what it means to be in love?
リーンのこれ
これが“好き”ってことなのか…
Gugu said what? What are you talking about?
グーグーが何？　何の話？
Is the person you like Gu—
リーンの好きな人って グー…
It's done!
（リーン）できた！
A crayfish face mask!
ザリガニ型フェイスマスク！
What do you think?
どう？
Looks good. Are you giving it to Gugu?
いいと思う
グーグーにあげるの？
What did you make, Fushi-san?
（リーン）フシさんは何作ったの？
A sweat rag for the old man.
じいの汗拭き布 ワキ用
For his pits.
Good job!
まあ 上手！
That's amazing.
すごい すごい…
きっと喜んでもらえるわ
I'm sure he'll love it.
Gugu?
（シン）グーグー？
It's you, isn't it?
（シン）グーグーだろ？
It's me. Your brother.
俺だ 兄ちゃんだ！
Aren't you going to ask him?
（フシ）言わないの？
（リーン）え？
Ask Gugu.
グーグーに
Ask him what?
何を？
To marry you.
ケッコンしてって
グ… グーグーの話なんて
してたっけ？
Were we ever talking about Gugu?
I thought we were.
そうだと思ってたけど
You know, don't you?
知ってるでしょ リーン
Gugu likes you.
グーグーはリーンのこと好きだよ
So I'm sure he'd be glad to marry you.
だからケッコン
喜んで受けてくれると思うよ
Man, I'm beat.
（酒爺(さけじい)）フィ～ しんどいのう
（フシ）あっ
Welcome home, old man.
じい おかえり
はい プレゼント！
Here. A gift.
What's that?
ん？　何じゃ それ？
Oh, a sweat rag for my pits!
おお ワキ用の汗拭き布か
こりゃ助かる ありがとう
That's great. Thank you.
I think I'll give my gift, too.
（リーン）私も渡してこようかな
（フシ）うん
Right.
Gugu's busy right now.
あ…
グーグーなら今 取り込み中だぞ
It's been a while.
久しぶりだな… 元気してたか？
How've you been?
You've changed a lot, huh?
ずいぶん変わったよな お前
その仮面どうしたんだよ？
What's up with that mask?
Are you hiding your face?
顔 隠してんのか？
I heard you live here.
ここで生活してるんだって？
How is it?
どうなんだ？　その…
I mean, are you enjoying it?
楽しいか？
No, I get it.
いや… そうか
If you're happy, I'm glad for you.
お前が幸せなら 俺も うれしいよ
I guess it was kind of a good thing
that you got away from me—
俺と離れて ある意味
正解だったのかも…
Why the hell are you here?!
（グーグー）一体 何をしに来た！
Did you want me to tell you
what a piece of trash you are?!
自分のクズさを
認めてもらいに来たのか？
（ピオラン）
ん？　どうした じいさん？
What's going on, old man?
Gugu's older brother is here.
グーグーの兄貴が来とる
I...
（シン）ほ…
I'm really sorry, Gugu.
本当に すまない グーグー
Something was wrong with me back then.
あの頃の俺は どうかしてた
Something was wrong with you?
（グーグー）どうかしてた？
違うよ 兄ちゃん
That's not it, Nii-chan.
That's who you really are.
あれが兄ちゃんの本質だよ
弟を裏切り 置き去りにした！
You betrayed and ditched your kid brother!
Y-You're right.
その… そのとおりだ
でも…
But...
But you gave me this.
でも お前は こんな俺に…
（グーグー）ハッ
You offered me your hand.
（シン）手を差し伸べてくれた
あっ ああ…
I'm sorry.
ごめんな
It took me four years to find you.
お前を見つけるまで
４年も かかっちまって…
I do work selling farm tools now.
今 俺 農具を売る仕事をしてるんだ
I just hired some people, and things
are finally becoming stable.
人を雇って
ようやく安定し始めたところだ
I eat properly every day.
ちゃんと毎日 食えてるし
Though our dream of building a
mansion is still a ways off...
屋敷を建てるって夢は
まだだけど…
I still want to realize that dream with you.
その夢は… お前と一緒に
かなえたいと思って
I want to make things right with you.
俺は お前に償いがしたい
And I want to start over.
そして やり直したい
You and I together, as brothers.
俺と お前… 兄弟２人の人生を
Will you come with me?
一緒に来ないか？
I'll pass.
（グーグー）断るよ
え…
It's true that being abandoned
by you made me miserable.
（グーグー）確かに 兄ちゃんに
捨てられたことは不幸だったよ
But what I gained by overcoming
it is practically a miracle for me.
でも それを乗り越えて
手に入れたものは
俺にとって奇跡に近いんだ
Booze Man, the unhinged
genius who saved my life.
イカれてるけど
天才で恩人の酒ジジイ
A knowledgeable and interesting grandma.
博識で 面白いバアさん
Kind Rean, who comes over once in a while.
ときどき遊びに来てくれる
優しいリーン
And Fushi, who's like a younger
brother and irreplaceable to me.
俺にとって代えがたいほど大切で
弟みたいな存在のフシ
I treasure all of them.
みんな大切な財産だ だから…
So please don't take anything
else away from me!
俺から もう二度と
取り上げないでくれ！
Yeah, of course.
ああ 当たり前だろ
Well, I have work to do.
（グーグー）
じゃあ 仕事があるから
You can always count on your big
brother to help you if you ever need it.
困ったことがあれば いつでも
兄ちゃんが助けるからな！
That's the only thing I can do...
それが…
俺にできる唯一の証明だから
to prove that I am your big brother.
俺が お前の兄貴だってことの…
W-Welcome.
い… いらっしゃい
Oh, are you done talking already?
ああ 話は もう終わったのかね？
Sorry for barging in.
急に押しかけて すみません
There's something I need
to give back to Gugu.
グーグーから
預かっていたものがあって
Here.
これ あいつに渡しておいて
くれませんか？
Could you pass this along to him?
All right.
（酒爺）ん… 分かった
Thank you.
（シン）ありがとうございます
Pardon me.
では…
What is it? What did he give you?
何なに？　何もらったの？
あっ
This is...
これ！
Well?
（リーンの父）どうだ？
お前にピッタリな指輪だろう？
Isn't that ring perfect for you?
I had a craftsman make it just for you.
職人に特別に作らせたんだ
I hate this color.
ヤダ！　こんな色…
What's the matter, Rean?
どうした リーン？
（リーン）あ…
Fresh produce here!
（グーグー）
らっしゃい らっしゃい
Fresh produce here!
らっしゃい らっしゃい！
That boy's here every day.
あの子 毎日あそこにいるわね
He is.
（侍女）そうですね
家の手伝いでしょうね
He must be helping his family.
Isn't it weird that he's working?
He's just a kid.
子供なのに
働いてるなんてヘンね
Poor boy.
かわいそう
Not at all.
It's very admirable of him.
いいえ
立派なことですわ
Oh, no.
（リーン）やん！
ミールったら また家出ね
Meer left home again.
I have to find him.
捜さないと…
Meer!
ミール！　ミール！　あ…
I have to thank him.
（リーン）お礼をしないとね
Oh...
そっか 君だったんだね
So that was you.
Are you all right?
大丈夫か？
Oh, yes. It's nothing.
ううん 何でもない
Hey, is it okay if I give him this?
（リーン）
ねえ 私が これ渡してきていい？
Sure. Thanks.
（酒爺）おお よろしく
Gugu!
グーグー！　グーグー！
（グーグーの寝息）
He's asleep.
寝ちゃってる？
（寝息）
んっ んん…
んん…
Ow, ow, ow!
（グーグー）イタタタ…
Rean!
わっ リーン？
何？　俺に何かした？
What?! Did you do something to me?!
Gugu, now's your chance
to make a move on me.
グーグー 私を口説くなら今よ！
What?
（グーグー）へ？
But... why...
な… んで？
Eh? Wha... Huh?
え？　な… ん？
I'm gonna be forced to get married soon.
私は もうすぐ結婚させられるの！
What? You are?!
（グーグー）えっ そうなの？
Are you okay with me getting
married to someone else?
私が ほかの誰かと
結婚しちゃってもいいの？
Wh-Why would you ask me that?!
（グーグー）えっ な… なんで
俺に そんなこと言うの？
You love me, don't you?!
私を愛してるんでしょ？
Huh?! What are you talking about?!
（グーグー）えっ 何のこと？
You said you did!
言ったじゃない！
That day you came back after running away!
あなたが家出から帰ってきた
あの日！
You said you were the one who
loved Rean-chan the most!
“リーンちゃんを
一番愛しているのは俺だ！”って
That's so embarrassing! I said that?!
（グーグー）えっ
そんな恥ずかしいこと言ったの？
I don't remember...
覚えてないよ…
Ow, ow!
（リーン）んんー
（グーグー）イタタタ…
My birthday party's happening next month!
来月 私の誕生日パーティーが
あるから 絶対来てね！
You'd better be there!
Huh?
（グーグー）へ？
What even was that?
何だったんだ？
Gone with the booze.
“酒と共に去りぬ”
Drinking makes you forget things.
酒を飲むと あらゆることが
忘れられ 消し去られてゆく
It erases them from memory.
You messed up, Gugu.
やっちまったな グーグー
And now, I have great news for you!
そんな お前に朗報！
（グーグー）ああ？
It's finally complete!
ついに完成した！
The all-new anti-Tree Man mask!
完全新作
対ツリーマン用仮面！
Tree Man?
（グーグー）ツリーマン？
You know, the thing that attacked
you a few years ago or whatever.
（酒爺）ほら 何年か前
お前とフシが襲われたとか何とか…
You made me this because of that?!
（グーグー）
それで これ作ってくれたの？
Yeah, it took a whole year.
おう １年かかったぞ
Go ahead, try it on.
さあ かぶってみろ
Whoa.
（グーグー）おお…
It's a bit heavy, but it's functional.
ちと重いが機能的だ
It can even make fire without a torch.
なんとタイマツがなくても
火が吹ける
Try closing the lid really fast.
そのフタを
勢いよく閉めてみるんだ！
There's a ball of tinder at the tip of the
nose that catches fire from the pressure.
圧で 鼻先に仕込んである着火玉に
火がつく！
（グーグー）グアッ
This is great, Booze Man!
すごいよ 酒ジジイ！　最高だ！
（酒爺の笑い声）
Awesome!
That'll be sure to impress her, too.
（酒爺）これで彼女もイチコロだ
Wear it to the party,
and you'll have her attention!
パーティーに かぶっていけば
注目されるぞ！
Thank you!
（グーグー）ありがとう
All right, then...
（グーグー）さてと…
Let's go, Fushi.
時間だぞ フシ
リーンの誕生会に遅れるぞ
We're going to be late for
Rean's birthday party.
Gugu, why don't you empty
the liquor in your belly?
グーグーよ 今日くらい
腹の酒をカラにしたら どうだ？
I'm sure you'll need space
for all that good grub.
ウマいメシ
たんまり食いたかろうに
Nah, it's fine.
（グーグー）いや いいよ
There's no telling when
the enemy will attack.
いつ敵が襲ってくるか
分からないからね
I want to be ready for the unexpected.
いざというときのために
万全でいたい
Okay, see you.
じゃ 行ってくるよ
Hang on, Gugu.
（酒爺）待て グーグー
（グーグー）ん？
You sure are a good kid.
お前は本当に いい子だな
We aren't related, but I really
do think of you as my grandson.
血は つながってないが
自分の孫のように思っとる
What brought that on? You're creeping me out.
（グーグー）
何だよ 急に？　気持ち悪い
Sorry.
（酒爺）いや すまんすまん
気をつけてな
Take care.
Okay, see you when we get back.
（グーグー）
じゃあ 留守番よろしく
Hey, how do you read maps?
（フシ）
ねえ 地図って どう見るの？
（酒爺の泣き声）
What are you sobbing for?
なーにを泣いとんじゃ！
He's only going to be away for a day!
たった１日の外出じゃろうに
Oh, I just got a bit worried.
いや ちょっと
心配になってしまってな
Seeing him come of age, it just hit me...
年頃になった あれを見たら
急に こみ上げてきた
Why am I such an old fart?
なんで俺は
ジジイなんだろうって思ってな…
I just can't stand the thought
that I'm going to die before him.
どうあっても グーグーより
先に死ぬのが悔しくてな
I want him to move out on his own, grow up,
あいつには家を出て大人になって
choose his own path,
and become what he wants.
好きな道を選んで
なりたいもんになって…
That's the kind of normal
life I want him to have.
そういう当たり前の人生を
送ってほしいんだ
And I want to die only after
I get to see all that happen.
それを全部まるっと見届けてから
俺は死にてえもんだ
What's in the bag?
（グーグー）その荷物 何？
Veggies.
野菜だよ
Pioran said I need bring gifts.
プレゼントが必要だって
ピオランが言ってたから
What are you bringing, Gugu?
グーグーは何あげるの？
I'm going to buy something up ahead.
（グーグー）
俺は この先で買うんだ
There! That's it!
おっ あった！　あれだ
Hello.
Welco—
（グーグー）こんちは
（店主）らっしゃ… うおっ
Welcome.
I'd like one of those purple flowers, please.
らっしゃい
（グーグー）その紫の花ください
Flowers?
花？
This is about the only thing I can
think of that Rean might like.
（グーグー）
リーンの好きそうなもの
これくらいしか思い浮かばなくて…
This flower's called the dream bellflower.
この花はユメキキョウって
いうんだよ
Huh...
（グーグー）へえ…
All right, we're here.
（グーグー）さあ 着いたぞ！
This is Rean's house!
リーンの家だ！
Man, her house is huge.
（グーグー）
でけえ所に住んでんだな
The floor's so shiny.
（フシ）床がツルツルだ
Look at all that yummy-looking food!
（グーグー）
見ろ ウマそうなメシだ！
I'll plate some for you.
取り分けてやる
You like pork, don't you?
お前 ブタ肉が好きだよな
They have noodles, too. And spring rolls.
麵もあるぞ あと春巻き
Grape juice for your drink,
and pear jelly for dessert.
飲み物は ぶどうジュース
デザートはナシモモのゼリーな
What's up with them?
（男性）何なんだ あいつら
Look at him with that mask.
It's supposed to be a festive event.
（女性）お祝いの席なのに
あんな仮面かぶって
How does he know Rean-san?
（男性）リーンさんと
どういう関係なんだろう？
Rean sure has a lot of friends.
（グーグー）リーンは友達が多いな
100人くらいか？
A hundred or so?
Meanwhile, Rean's our only friend, right?
俺らの友達はリーン１人なのにな
My.
（リーン）あら 光栄だわ
What an honor.
Rean.
（フシ）リーン！
（グーグー）うわっ
Thanks for coming today.
今日は来てくれて ありがとう
Look.
The old man made Gugu a new mask.
見て じいがグーグーの仮面
新しくしてくれたんだよ
So I see. It's lovely.
（リーン）ホント！　すてきだわ
（グーグー）あああ… あ…
（グーグー）うっ…
あ…
Hey, Rean...
（グーグー）あのさ リーン
Can I ask you something about the other day?
こないだのことで
ちょっと聞きたいんだけど…
The other day?
こないだ？
Oh, sorry for throwing potatoes at you.
ああ！　おイモ投げちゃって
ごめんね
Potatoes?
イモ？
Did I break your mask?
もしかして
仮面 割れちゃったのかな？
That's why you got a new one, huh?
だから新しくしたのね？
ホントごめんね
I'm sorry! Really!
No, that's not...
（グーグー）
いや そうじゃなくて…
What are these?
うわあ… これ何？
もしかして私へのプレゼント？
Are these your gifts for me?
Yeah. Veggies.
うん 野菜だよ
Thank you!
ありがとう！
Give her yours, too, Gugu.
ほら グーグーも
Here.
（グーグー）これ
Happy sixteenth birthday.
16歳おめでとう
Isn't that flower...
（男性）あの花って確か…
What does he think he's doing?
（男性）一体どういうつもりだ？
Gugu...
グーグー
なんで この花を選んだの？
Why did you choose this flower?
Oh, I just thought you might like that one...
（グーグー）えっ いやあ…
その花 好きそうだなって
思って… 紫だし！
Since it's purple.
That's the flower she was holding
when she was injured four years ago.
それは４年前
お嬢さまが事故に遭われたときに
持っていらした花ですよ
Did you want to hurt her?
あなたは お嬢さまを
傷つけたいのですか？
（グーグー）えっ！
I'm sorry, Rean!
ごめん リーン！
気がつかなくて
I didn't know!
It's fine.
いいのよ じゃ楽しんでね
Anyway, have fun.
（グーグー）うう… やっちまった
I blew it!
What were you doing with potatoes?
イモで何してたの？
These flowers are so pretty.
（リーン）わあ きれいな花ね
なんて名前かしら
I wonder what they're called.
I'd love to wear a dress in this color.
こんな色のドレスが着たいわ…
キャッ
（衝撃音）
That was the first time I saw this flower.
あの日 初めて見て それ以来
見ることのなかった花なのに…
And I never saw one since.
Rean, give me that flower.
（リーンの母）リーン その花…
I'll throw it out for you.
It'll bring back memories, won't it?
捨てておくわ
思い出しちゃうでしょう
No.
ダメ… 初めて あの人に
もらったものなんだもの
It's the first time he ever gave me anything.
Hey, handsome.
（男性）よう イケメン
I'm talking to you, with the mask.
（男性）仮面！　お前のことだよ
（グーグー）え？
I've been watching you.
（男性）さっきから見てたけど
お前 失礼じゃないか？
Don't you think you're being rude?
Take that thing off.
そのツラ外せよ 祝いの席だぞ
This is a celebration.
Yeah, I know.
（グーグー）ああ 分かってる…
けど無理なんだ
But I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
（男性）何が無理なんだ！
（グーグー）ああ… ちょっと…
Wait!
You look dumb in that mask!
（男性）
似合ってないぜ この仮面！
（グーグー）うわっ
（フシ）あ…
（水の音と悲鳴）
ハッ
What's going on?
（リーン）何事！
He fell in by himself.
（男性）こいつが勝手に
落ちただけです
Hurry, get a towel.
（リーン）まあ… 早くタオルを！
Here.
You're going to get wet, young lady!
（リーン）はい
（侍女）お嬢さま ぬれますわ！
Come on, dry your face off with this.
ほら これで顔を拭いて…
あっ
（グーグー）う…
Sheesh.
ヤダ これじゃあ…
With this thing on, you'll never
be able to kiss anyone.
あなた このままじゃ
一生 誰ともキスできないわね
（招待客たちの失笑）
Young lady!
お嬢さま！　お父さまが
呼んでいらっしゃいます
Your father is calling.
Coming.
Get all dried off so you don't catch a cold.
ええ
じゃ 風邪ひかないように
よく拭いてね
Rean!
リーン 紹介しよう
Allow me to introduce you
to your betrothed.
お前の結婚相手だ
え？
So you're Rean-chan, huh?
（婚約者）君がリーンちゃんか
目が大きくて かわいいね
You're very cute with those big eyes.
Ready to go home, Fushi?
（グーグー）もう帰ろうか フシ
Huh? But I want to eat more.
えっ まだ食べたいのに
Fushi...
（グーグー）フシ…
I thought Rean would always be part
of our lives, coming over all the time,
俺は この先 リーンが
うちに遊びに来てくれる日常が
ずっと続いてくんだと思ってたよ
but it won't be that way.
でも… これからは違う
Why not?
どうして？
I think it's because...
（グーグー）きっと それが…
そういうルールなんだ
Because those are the rules.
Who decided that?
誰が決めたの？
Your life isn't something given to you.
It's for you to win for yourself, Gugu!
自分の生き方は
自分で勝ち取るんだ グーグー！
Did you come up with that line yourself?
（グーグー）
そのセリフ お前が考えたのか？
No.
（フシ）違う
（グーグー）だはっ
ハァ…
Go eat. I'll be waiting outside.
メシ食ってろ 外で待ってる
Gugu!
（リーン）グーグー！
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
You're leaving already?
もう帰っちゃうの？
Are you angry about what happened in there?
ひょっとして怒ってる
さっきのこと？
No. I'm used to it.
（グーグー）いいや もう慣れてる
You might not like this,
but can I ask you again?
（リーン）
あなたは嫌がるかもしれないけど
もう一度 聞いていいかな？
About your mask... and your injury?
その仮面… ケガのこと
Don't worry.
大丈夫！　何を聞いても
嫌いにならない自信あるわ
I'm sure I won't hate you,
no matter what you say.
I fell from a cliff.
（グーグー）崖から落ちたんだ
According to Booze Man, when he
found me, there was a log on my head.
酒ジジイが言うには
見つかったとき
頭に丸太が のっかってた
That's how my face got smashed in.
それで顔が 潰れたんだ
Why did you fall off the cliff?
どうして崖から落ちたの？
The log was rolling down a hill.
（グーグー）丸太が坂を転がってさ
It was about to hit someone ahead.
その先に人がいたんだ
I shouted, but they didn't notice me,
叫んだけど 気づいてくれなくて
so I ran to try to help them...
走って助けようとした
and I screwed up.
そこでヘマした
Why were you hiding this from me?
なんで そんなこと隠してたの？
That's such a noble thing to do.
とても立派なことよ
Because I screwed up even worse than that.
（グーグー）
もっと大きなヘマをしたからさ
Did that person not make it?
その人は助からなかったの？
No, they made it.
（グーグー）いや 一応 助かった
But they ended up with
an injury about this big.
だけど…
このくらいの傷が残った
That's just a scratch
compared to your injury.
そんなの あなたのケガに比べたら
ほんの かすり傷よ
But to her, it was a huge injury.
（グーグー）でも
その子にとっては大きな傷だった
It really bothered her.
すごく悩んでたんだ
She was too embarrassed
to let anyone see it.
恥ずかしくて人に見せられないって
I felt so bad for what I had done.
ひどいことをしたと思ったよ
あ…
（グーグー）ん？
But you saved that girl's life.
でも その子は
あなたに命を救われたわ！
（木々が風に揺れる音）
Want me to take a guess, Gugu?
（リーン）
当ててあげよっか グーグー
It was windy that day.
その日は風が強かった
Yeah.
（グーグー）うん
There was a river there.
その場所には川が流れてたわ
It was around sunset.
時間は夕方… 花が咲いてた
Flowers were blooming.
Yeah.
（グーグー）うん
Purple flowers.
紫色の花…
その子は それを持ってたの
She was holding some of them.
Yeah. I heard they're
called dream bellflowers.
（グーグー）うん その花も
ユメキキョウって
いうんだってね
Gugu, I...
（リーン）グーグー 私ね…
キャッ
Gugu!
グーグー！
They're here.
It's the Nokkers.
（観察者）来たぞ ノッカーだ